look i i can't understand what you're
saying
you need to speak english
i have one but i do have a new friend
that i made this english guy in my
neighborhood england english people
think i'm a genius like no matter what i
say like
i'm gonna go to a store to buy some eggs
oh that's brilliant
i'm buying the eggs i'm not laying them
that would be brilliant
this guy you know i have to get them
acclimated to new york it's a very you
know it's confusing it's a confusing
place and he's
so i've become like his you know tour
guide and stuff so he wanted he had
never been on the subway
he wanted to bring his bike on the
subway so he hired me to negotiate the
deal
you know so i had to go down there but
before i could say anything he got into
an argument with the subway token booth
clerk
nobody can make themselves understood it
was like a cultural impasse you know
excuse me right i've got i've got this
bicycle
i'd like to bring the bicycle on the
tube i bring the bicycle
onto you
and what you gonna do you gonna take
that car you gonna slide it
through the slot cheers pretty i've got
a bar
school the wheel was changing i'd like
to bring the body school on youtube
you gonna take that card you're gonna
slide it
through the slot the line the line with
the money at just
you need to speak english
hey don't you man it is a choo-choo
train
the dude just snapped he looks and he's
like bruh how do you new yorkers
understand each other i was like
knowledge
so it's it for me this is a real treat
to be here i get to get out of new york
a little bit
you know we went on a vacation
that didn't go well you know i was all
excited my wife surprised me she's like
we're going to uh we're going to costa
rica
right i've never been there so i'm like
okay she didn't tell me we're staying
in the jungle she's like it's a health
resort in the jungle because you know
that's where you go to get healthy
is the jungle hey you're losing weight
you're working out now that
seats you fly by you've got a little
malaria you know sweating for
32 weights pretty good one week
so i packed nice stuff i got a little
great gatsby alligator belt you know i
don't have my you know shawshank
redemption outfit on them all we're
getting ready
and we find i'm scared of flying that's
another thing so we fly the normal plane
but to get there once you land you've
got to catch one of those little planes
and those are the those are the scariest
like the pilot if you're scared of
flying
the pilot starts it with the hand and
this pilot had an eye patch
and the other eye was lazy it was
looking where the old i used to be i'm
like oh this that's not going to be good
so the plane takes off the engine
doesn't sound good it sounds like
somebody sucked up a penny with a dust
buster like
i'm like we're gonna die so and the
pilot he senses i'm scared it's only us
on the plane so he keeps looking back
and winking with the remaining eye i'm
like make that eye look that way you
know because every time it opens it's
looking different directions like lemons
oranges
you know make it look that way it could
be geeks or something he's like
you know
so then we land right now we got to
catch a raft to the jungle
i'm not hug finn i've never been on a
raft you know
some little apprehensive so the guy
comes over who's taking us
and i'm asking him questions you know
that i think are normal questions i'm
like you got a
a raft license you went to raft school
or something a certificate i can see
and the guy's not friendly at all he
says one thing to me he's like
in the jungle there is no he was
kind of passive aggressive right kind of
passive aggression
so i'm on a raft we're going down the
river i'm marinating on this statement
you know and i look on one side and
there's trees
and another side this tree that has
fallen all of a sudden it sprouts eyes
and legs and starts following us i'm
like oh that's a crocodile
you know i better tell the guy i'm like
uh there's a crocodile back there he's
like it's time
i mean it's time for what it is time to
battle i'm like you got the only pedal
what do i use the hand i'm not putting a
hand in the water
i saw that movie with j-lo an ice cube
and stuff jumps out of the water all i
could think is a crocodile saw the belt
and wanted revenge you know you killed
my cousin
so we make it to the land
and uh we're seeing in huts and
uh again there's no costa ricans there
there's no americans there's only
germans
uh i don't understand if you ever go to
a hot place there's always germans there
all you know it's a very painful
sounding language and
they're always sunburned red and they
have the little tiny bathing suits that
leave nothing to the imagination
you know the little hammocks
with the whole fruit bowls in there and
and i think that's how that language got
invented you know thousands of years ago
jerome went to a hot place got all
sunburned like ooh
my butt on fire just how he thought from
now on get down
so uh i start unloading my stuff the guy
comes always like don't leave the
clothes out because in the night
the howler monkey coming you're taking
the clothes you're on it
i said the what the howling monkey come
here taking the clothes
you i know in brooklyn i'm not worried
about the howler monkey
like the other night uh a rat ran over
my foot i was wearing flip-flops and it
tickled
so i go to sleep i wake up the next day
all my stuff is gone i look up in the
tree there's a holler monkey up there
he's got my shirt on he's got the collar
popped all 80s it's the 80s howler
monkey
i know he's stolen stuff where the
sleeves are rolled up on him
so now my wife wants to go on a hike in
the jungle right so it's just myself
her and the guide and it's funny
situations i don't know if you guys ever
been in this situation when you're out
of your element and the person
in charge takes takes liberties takes
control
you know like this guy uh he's kind of
hitting on my wife in front of me
you know showing her the features of the
jungle in great detail my turn he loses
enthusiasm he has a machete it's a
really awkward
situation you know he'll be like lulu
break the
leaf and chew that one doesn't like the
toothpaste for the nature
for the lady i'm like what's that
leaf you know
you don't say leaf before
[Music]
look that one dusty jesus christmaser
because he run on top of the water
like jesus i'm like what's that i look
at the leaf
he walked too slow under him
and then he starts trying to scare me
it's like what's that sound i'm like
what sound he's like dichoncho de
chancho
he smelled the gringo he know they have
the money this makes him very angry
like how do you get away from the
chancho you climbed the tree but the
chancho know you in the tree
he pee-pee around the base of the tree
the chancho peepee special come out like
a concentrate
you breathe there you feel woozy you
fall out of the tree that chance
you die so now i'm terrified that this
pig with a raging urinary tract
infection and a working degree of
economics is going to come running out
of the jungle
three hours later no chancho and now
this guy wants a tip and all of a sudden
his english gets really good he's like i
don't know if you saw but there's a 20
gratuity at the bottom of that contract
i looked at him i was like indie jungle
there is no law
hey guys uh i know you guys are looking
at me like this dude's not gonna be
funny
looks like he's going to give a lecture
about considering a career in law
enforcement
yeah if people don't think i'm going to
be funny you know
they ask me for directions a lot that
happens a lot
it happened just outside the hotel you
know i don't know where anything
this lady comes up where's the post
office where's the post office you want
to tell them something so i was like
uh go straight make a right then another
right then another right when you get
back here
ask somebody who knows
good to be here in indiana jones's
living room
i'm a comedian my wife is a psychologist
so she uh
fixes people's problems all day i make
fun of him all night that's not how that
works
we live in brooklyn new york brooklyn
new york it's uh
it's kind of fancy now it's like dogs
with uggs and stuff and
you know but i did hear this argument
out of the window the other day one guy
shouts at another guy you know what the
real n word is
knowledge
[Music]
you see stuff in brooklyn you don't see
anywhere else i was walking through the
park the other day i see this old man
doing tai chi i'm like ah that's cool
then i look closer it's not an old man
doing tai chi it's one of those heroin
guys it never falls over
i think that's who designed this set i
think that's what designed this set
i didn't grow up in brooklyn i grew up
in washington d.c
i went to uh yeah i went to dc public
schools the only school system with
white history month
uh
i was the only white kid on my class for
the school play i was the snow storm i
just ran across stage naked
then i moved to new york i moved to
brooklyn and
my neighborhood was hostile when i moved
there like the first is 30 years ago the
first day i'm there getting a
confrontation
you know with this guy you know i ought
to i don't bust your face
i don't bust your face you stand on my
block you don't show no respect you look
in my eye
i had to bust your face i was like look
officer i'm just trying to
[Music]
trying to acclimate myself so i'm a
jewish comedian married to a black woman
with a phd
who looks like an indian we live in an
italian name in brooklyn everybody
thinks i'm puerto rican
you know so puerto ricans think i'm a
cop
i play a lot of cops and in shows and
stuff like that but
most of the time i play bad guys like uh
a while ago i had an audition for a show
called swift justice which you can tell
by the name
there's gonna be a really bad show you
know and i always play like flocco the
drug dealer and i have one line and the
line is i'm gonna cut you good
you know so i'm practicing in the
apartment i'm doing to the cat you know
i'm gonna cut you good
you know do it to my wife i'm gonna cut
you good she's like take out the trash
i'm like
you know i memorized live so
i go to the audition the next day
there's 30 guys look just like me
sitting there we're going to cut you
you know i'm nervous cass director comes
out he messes up my name dc benny he's
like
jc penny yeah come on
i walk in i'm so nervous i forget the
line so i improvise something i'm like
i'll kill all you fools and i just leave
right
and i get the part i get the party
second i'm very excited you know
practicing we the day we shoot it we
shoot it everything's great and then uh
the night it comes on i tell everybody
my whole family was sitting there
watching the part comes
i'm nowhere to be found i'm like what
happened my wife's saying
[Music]
my wife has an uncle uh named willy and
he's one of those dudes that uh is
obsessed with racism
you know he's uh he's always telling me
all these different theories he has like
everybody came from the black man reason
nobody knows about it is because the fbi
has suppressed this evidence he's like
look here what's fbi stand for
false black information frogging up a
brother's identity what's the cia
caucasians and then alibis
everybody black jewish people came from
the black man what did jewish people say
oi what's oil backwards yo
same thing same thing italians are black
sicily
named after who sis lit tyson italy is
in the shape of a boot cause a brother
when timberland has discovered it
even scottish people are black wear them
skirts called kilts why you stick your
hand under it you're gonna get killed
i'm like who is white then anybody named
bob
bob is a secret cia co-worker for back
of the bus that's why you don't ever see
a brother named bob no brothers and we
call rob because when he can't find no
job he robbed
[Music]
[Applause]
so the neighborhood i live in i just got
out of a seven year
vendetta with a neighbor over over a
parking space
uh i live in this old school italian
neighborhood right there's one guy there
this violent old man
you know he's got a he's got a tomato
plant from the house he keeps a lead
pipe in it
you know it's not in plumbing just to
threaten people with it
he's got he takes up four parking spaces
he's got three cars he puts cones in
between
takes up four spaces which is incredibly
there's no parking there at all it's
just so annoying so i'm a scorpio i'm a
little vindictive whenever i
see one of his faces open i park into
space
and he does stuff to my car that's how
this whole thing started like the first
time
i saw the space opener i parked in the
space i come back there's a hard-boiled
egg stuffed in the exhaust
over the phone okay okay so wait wait
until it gets a little uh
warm he cracks the windows in one of his
car i filled up his car i had a
big bag of glitter i filled it up with
glitter
and i know he cleaned it out because he
had sprinkles on his face for like a
week you know he looked like a he looked
like a stripper but he didn't smell like
yankee vanilla candles
a little time goes by a little time goes
i see the space open i park into space
right i come back the next day
the gas flap is open the cap is missing
there's an empty bag of domino sugar
duct taped to the to the top of the car
like you put sugar in my gas tank
so we'll put a neutral roll to the gas
station and have the guys look at it
they're like no there doesn't seem to be
any sugar residue but uh it seems like
somebody's trying to send you a message
oh was it sicily in 1821
so like okay all right so wait till it
gets cold i take his cones i get them
wet on the bottom i stick them on the
top of each car and they freeze like
sirens like sirens
i drive by when he's trying to break one
off i'm like whoop whoop and then i
drive off
right now
a little time goes by a little time goes
by alternate side parking
you know we gotta move the cars one side
to the other is suspended for a week
so i see the space open i park in there
i leave it for a week out of spite
right i take the train out of spot it's
beautiful
right i come back at the end of the week
there are eight slices of bologna on the
hood of my car that have been sitting
there it doesn't sound like a big deal
but here's the thing about bologna is
how bad it is for your digestive system
if you leave it on the hood of a car for
more than three and a half days it
adheres to the paint
so when you pull it off it takes a big
circle of paint with it so i have this
polka dot hood
permanently poking out at hood and this
guy's yelling stuff out of the window
these old world war ii insults you know
send a salami to your boy in the army
i'm always like let it go let it go
whatever so then like another week like
i said i park in this space or whatever
i come back
the windshield's cracked i got four flat
tires he's keyed the car
he's broken off the antenna i'm about to
lose my my mind my wife's like just let
it go
let it go this guy's crazy you're out of
your league right
you know but in my heart i want revenge
i'll let it go well uh about a month ago
the dude dies and i had nothing to do
with it i mean i wasn't there this is
i'm not gonna say i'm sorry because i'm
not but um
but still it's a human life you gotta do
the right thing i i see his wife a
couple weeks ago so
like how i just want to extend my
condolences
about anthony's untimely demise
uh hopefully he's in a better place
you know with more abundant parking and
uh
and we had a moment together we had a
moment she gets all teary-eyed she's
like you know you're the only one
that said anything and the whole
neighborhood the only one that said
anything because a lot of people didn't
notice
anthony anthony was very sick for the
last five years
that is why he acted the way he did and
she goes really
there was only one thing that kept him
going i'm like
what was that she's like he hated you
we got all kinds of stuff in our
neighborhood we got a fortune teller
you ever go to a fortune teller i'm like
i gotta try it this lady was predicting
the most unamazing stuff she had a
crystal ball
yeah it's like i see in your future tall
dark man
with big forehead i'm like that's my
reflection
silence do not mock the power i see your
cambodian
no canadian no custodian yes you're
because i'm a comedian we got spell
check on this vault he's
do you see refund
[Laughter]
well now they did a show in amsterdam
that was cool i met a guy that lived in
a windmill
i was like how do you bring girls home
to a windmill it's like you have to be
very careful you have to time it
i did a show in jamaica i got stopped at
customs the ladies going through my
stuff you know are you bringing any
drugs into jamaica i was like drugs into
jamaica
it's like bringing slim fast in ethiopia
all the ethiopians here tonight are
gonna get
you know i try not to you know like uh
my friends
people get pretty sensitive now
everybody got so sensitive i don't know
when this stuff happened you know like i
had a friend who used to be my friend uh
he came over the other days he's like
i'm hungry like okay so i think
i fixed him a sandwich and he's like
well i can't eat that
and i said well why not he's like well
because i have a gluten allergy i'm like
what are the symptoms he's like we feel
full and tired i'm like that's what's
supposed to happen after you eat bread
not supposed to be famished and
local alert robs wendy's with alligator
for the alligator boys now and the lady
they sent them to the bank should be
going mom
[Music]
mom